#### SR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

786 619 5583 • javi830810@gmail.com

## Solutions-oriented developer. Polyglot. Computer Science Theorist.

Software Engineer, with 10 years of experience in the software industry, go-getter, and over achiever. Experience in Workforce, Education, Advertising, E-Commerce, and Communication Systems. Experienced team leader. Keen on minimalist software, generally dislike ORMs and over engineering.

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, C#, JavaScript, PHP, HTML5, LESS, SASS, CSS3

Server Development: NET, ASP.NET MVC, NServiceBus, LINQ, Castle Windsor,

Spring.Net, LINQ, Webapp2 (Python)

Web Development: JQuery, AngularJS, EmberJS, Backbone, Swagger, REST, SOAP,

Ajax, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bower

Cloud: GoogleAppEngine, Azure, AWS, Heroku

Database Systems: | SQL Server, MongoDB, RavenDB, Redis, Memcached, Neo4J

**Source Control:** GIT, SVN, Mercurial

**Testing:** NUnit, Nose (python)

**Concepts:** OOP, Functional Programming, CQRS, TDD, Continuous Integration

(Travis, Team City, Capistrano), Agile (SCRUM, Kanban),

Task Automation: | Bash, Grunt

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Software Engineer at Kaplan, Inc.

**2014 - Present** 

Education. Backend developer, corporate environment, integration with company's internal APIs and closely worked with Product Owners to convert requirements into features. Architect of Scalebridge.

 Scalebridge. Integration platform that handles processing and post-delivery of messages between separated systems. Communication happens agnostically and through Scalebridge. Hosted at <a href="http://scalebridge.appspot.com/">http://scalebridge.appspot.com/</a>

<sup>\*</sup> References available upon request.

 KAPx. Learning Platform for online courses. Integration with learning management systems, like Moodle. Multi-tenant suite where different universities host courses and process student operations like tuitions, credits, grades etc. Hosted at http://kapx.kaplan.com/

**Technology**: Python Swagger Memcached GoogleAppEngine AngularJS Grunt Bower Git

#### Founder/Software Engineer at XPLOT, Inc.

2013 - Present

Entrepreneurship. Personal entrepreneurial adventure to explore ideas, develop and grow personal projects. Focused on the Event planning market, and notifications to big groups of people fast and reliably.

 iMeet. Platform to support event organization and party planning. Includes a wide range of features, including but not limited to: Dispatch SMS, IVR, Email, a Crowdfunding API, and Address Book management. Hosted at <a href="http://imeet.io/">http://imeet.io/</a>

Technology: C# Python AspNetMVC Webapp2 Azure GoogleAppEngine Backbone Grunt Git

## Manager of Digital Development at Zubi Advertising, Inc.

2013 - 2014

Advertising. In-house development leader and manager of all outsourced projects; Designed and executed development of an infrastructure for internal Software Practices, like source control, cloud hosting and continuous integration.

- HTML5 Ad Campaigns for Yahoo, MSN and Huffington Post full-page takeovers, as part of a campaign for Ford Motors.
- Zubiad. Architecture and implementation of the company website, superb web experience, responsive on desktop, mobile. Hosted at <a href="http://www.zubiad.com">http://www.zubiad.com</a>

Technology: C# PHP HTML5 Grunt Capistrano CSS3 jQuery Git

# Software Engineer at JDA Software

2010 - 2013

Workforce. Backend developer, worked on highly used and distributed services. Built REST APIs that interacted with Workforce Platforms (Kronos, Infor), also worked extensively with Communication platforms such as Twilio, Voxeo for the distribution of notifications.

 Orbit. Communications platform, high performance; able to distribute 100 SMS per second and able to handle as many incoming responses. Main architect of this system from scratch built it into a core value for the company.

<sup>\*</sup> References available upon request.

- Shiftex. Shift Manager for employers. Event based architecture. It's currently handing out more than 3000 work shifts a day to potential employees, in stores like Kohl's and Nike.
- Alerts. Emergency system for the New York and New Jersey Port Authority. Used for high reliability and fast response alert broadcast.
- LSS. Employee Address Book for Lutheran Social Services of Michigan. Manages an average of around 2000 employees' daily updates.

Technology: C# AspNetMVC NServiceBus WCF SQLServer RavenDb Memcached Nuget SVN

## Software Developer at CIMEX Corporation

2005 - 2010

Ecommerce. Online store for biggest Cuban retailer. This nationwide site produces revenue of \$50K+ monthly. Designed to be themed differently, it supports at the current time different stores all across Cuba. This project is the perfect mockup of an ecommerce suite.

CarlosTercero. Online virtual shop for the biggest Cuban retailer, selling products nationwide.
 Built using best pattern and practices including but not limited Dependency Injection, NTier design, Domain Driven Design, etc. Hosted at <a href="http://www.carlostercero.ca">http://www.carlostercero.ca</a>

Technology: C# ASP.NET 2.0 SQL Server SVN

### **EDUCATION**

Graduate studies	Introduction to Artificial Intelligence Stanford University, USA <a href="https://www.udacity.com/course/intro-to-artificial-intelligencecs271">https://www.udacity.com/course/intro-to-artificial-intelligencecs271</a>	Dec 2011
Bachelor's Degree	Computer Science (GPA of 4.3 of 5) Havana University	Jun 2007

## Find me on:

Github: <a href="http://github.com/javi830810">http://github.com/javi830810</a>
Twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/javi830810">http://twitter.com/javi830810</a>

in LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/javi830810

StackOverflow: <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/71957/javi830810">http://stackoverflow.com/users/71957/javi830810</a>

Wordpress: <a href="http://javi830810.wordpress.com/">http://javi830810.wordpress.com/</a>

<sup>\*</sup> References available upon request.